<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2020-2022 Matt Pharoah -->
<component type="desktop-application">
	<id>ca.parallel_launcher.ParallelLauncher</id>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">ca.parallel_launcher.ParallelLauncher.desktop</launchable>
	<name>Parallel Launcher</name>
	<summary>A simple easy-to-use launcher for the ParallelN64 and Mupen64Plus-Next emulators</summary>
	<developer_name>Matt Pharoah</developer_name>
	<url type="homepage">https://parallel-launcher.ca</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://gitlab.com/parallel-launcher/parallel-launcher/-/boards/2128467</url>
	<url type="help">https://parallel-launcher.ca/doc/parallel-launcher-manual.pdf</url>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<caption>Classic View</caption>
			<image type="source">https://parallel-launcher.ca/img/screenshot.png</image>
		</screenshot>
		<screenshot>
			<caption>RHDC View</caption>
			<image type="source">https://parallel-launcher.ca/img/rhdc-view.png</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<description>
		<p>Parallel Launcher is an emulator launcher that aims to make playing N64 games, both retail and homebrew, as simple and as accessible as possible. Parallel Launcher uses the RetroArch emulator, but replaces its confusing menus and controller setup with a much simpler user interface. It also features optional integration with romhacking.com.</p>
	</description>
	<project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
	<metadata_license>GFDL-1.3</metadata_license>
	<icon type="remote">https://parallel-launcher.ca/img/appicon.svg</icon>
	<categories>
		<category>Game</category>
	</categories>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>N64</keyword>
		<keyword>Emulator</keyword>
	</keywords>
	<provides>
		<mediatype>application/x-n64-rom</mediatype>
		<mediatype>application/x-bps-patch</mediatype>
		<mediatype>x-scheme-handler/rhdc</mediatype>
		<binary>parallel-launcher</binary>
	</provides>
	<recommends>
		<control>gamepad</control>
	</recommends>
	<translation type="qt" source_locale="en_CA">parallel-launcher</translation>
	<releases>
		<release version="v6.6.2" date="2022-05-15">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Fixed the Now Playing window always appearing in the top left corner</li>
					<li>Fixed the Now Playing window having its title bar offscreen on Windows</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.6.1" date="2022-05-12">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Reverted to launching RetroArch with normal priority on Windows</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.6.0" date="2022-05-09">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>The "Widescreen (Viewport Hack)" option will now use 16:10 widescreen on the Steam Deck instead of 16:9, so it now fills the entire screen.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.5.0" date="2022-05-08">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Parallel Launcher will now always check romhacking.com for graphics plugin recommendations when finding new roms, even if RHDC Integration is disabled.</li>
					<li>Disabled integer scaling for the ParaLLEl plugin. It will now always scale to fill the window.</li>
					<li>Fixed the RHDC icon being tiny on high DPI displays</li>
					<li>RetroArch is now launched with a higher process priority on the Windows version</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.4.2" date="2022-04-29">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Fixed the GoldenEye input mode mapping the triggers incorrectly</li>
					<li>Fixed icon-only buttons being too small on high dpi monitors</li>
					<li>Removed the warning when starting Parallel Launcher in gaming mode on the Steam Deck</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.4.1" date="2022-04-24">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Fixed a bug where opening a .bps patch from an external file browser would create a corrupted rom entry in the Parallel Launcher classic view</li>
					<li>Removed the 'Automatically Added' category. Roms added by launching them from a file browser now just go into Uncategorized</li>
					<li>Fixed a bug where the controller deadzone and sensitivity settings were not being applied for users whose locale settings use a comma instead of a period for the decimal separator.</li>
					<li>Slightly changed the buttons in the controller selection and setup dialogs to be less confusing when creating a new profile from a default.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.4.0-flatpak1" date="2022-04-20">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Fixed save states not working in the ParallelN64-Next core in the Flatpak release of Parallel Launcher</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.4.0" date="2022-04-19">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Tweaked various things when playing on Steam Deck for a better user experience</li>
					<li>Changed the layout of the RHDC view to be more horizontal</li>
					<li>Enable Discord integration by default in the Flatpak version</li>
					<li>Renamed the ParallelN64 core file to ensure RetroArch will never overwrite it</li>
					<li>The Parallel Launcher window now has two separate sizes that it saves separately for the classic and RHDC views</li>
					<li>Fixed a bug where the RHDC view would not remember your last selected ROM on startup</li>
					<li>Fixed graphical bugs in the RHDC view when horizontally resizing the window</li>
					<li>Fixed the last few controller mappings going to the wrong inputs when using Quick Configure</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="v6.3.0" date="2022-04-18">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Added a Flatpak version of Parallel Launcher</li>
					<li>Tweaked some settings and behaviour when playing on Steam Deck for better usability</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
	</releases>
</component>
